# **RESUME- Miriam Katunze**

Fu Tei, Tuen Mun, Hong Kong +852 59349286/ +256788116480

miriam.katunze@gmail.com/ miriamkatunze@ln.hk

Date of Birth: 21/11/1984 Nationality: Ugandan

## **Professional Summary**

Detail-orientated development Economics Researcher with an extensive background in analyzing various types of data and collating results. Employing meticulous attention to detail to produce in-depth research and policy reports. Excellent computer literacy with notable skills in various data analyzing software.

## **Experience**

Lingnan University

September 2018 to Current

#### **Tutor**

Tuen Mun, New Territories, Hong Kong

- Devised unique lessons to fit individual needs in skill building and full instruction on each subject.
- Gave early intervention support to students just beginning to struggle with materials.
- Answered email message and telephone calls to provide quick assistance.
- Assisted students of all skill levels in Economics.
- Completed logs and updated student documents.
- Utilised technology in tutoring sessions to diversify and enhance learning.
- Helped students with subject knowledge as well as general abilities in learning, studying and retaining information.
- Used moodle and ICT materials to engage students during class lectures.

Economic Policy Research Center, EPRC

August 2013 to September 2018

#### **Research Analyst**

Kampala, Uganda

- Collected data on consumers, marketplace and competitors, consolidating information into actionable items, reports and presentations.
- Stayed up to date on market trends through ongoing research and analysing policies, increasing company awareness of threats and opportunities.
- Extracted, analysed, visualised and reported on data and marketing insights on agriculture and economics, supporting policy activities.
- Collected data through the web and statistics bureau, analysing areas for opportunities and business growth.
- Organised events to establish community relationships and maximise marketing strategies.
- Produced marketing graphics that were attractive and high-quality by applying skills in STATA.

Gayaza High School

January 2008 to September 2009

#### Teacher of French

Wakiso, Uganda

- Provided excellent leadership skills to maintain steady and productive operations.
- Spearheaded special projects and resolved complex problems that impacted management and business direction.
- Assisted in developing advertising and marketing strategies using social media platforms.
- Supported financial and business forecasts to facilitate accurate budgets.

- Customised products to meet user specifications improving customer experience.
- Developed expertise and knowledge in French to ensure consistent delivery of outstanding foreign language services.

Ndejje Senior Secondary School

January 2007 to December 2007

#### **Teacher**

Luweero, Uganda

- Of French, Ndejje Senior Secondary School (Luwero, Uganda).
- Interacted with students and promoted good behaviour through positive reinforcement methods.
- Established clear objectives for all lessons, units and projects.
- Employed teaching techniques to encourage student learning and build community within the classroom.
- Created and implemented developmentally-appropriate curriculum which addressed individual learning styles.
- Observed children and recorded activities, maintained daily records and created safe environments during activities, meals and naps.
- Worked outside normal hours to be available to answer parent and student questions.
- Employed a broad range of instructional techniques to retain student interest and maximise learning.
- Taught after-school and summer enrichment programmes.

## **Core Qualifications**

Academic

• Balance

• Budget Analysis

• Conferences

• Decision-making

• Delivery

• DFID

• Economics

• English

• Finance

• French

Government

• Grants

Investments

Market

Exchange

Policies

• Presenter

Publications

Research

Statistics

• Tax

• Designing surveys

• Analysing data

 Expert in STATA, EViews, SPSS, MLWIN, NVIVO

## Education

**Lingnan University** 

2018 (to be attained November 2021)

2012

**Ph.D**: Economics

Hong Kong

Thesis topic: How Do Contracting, Co-Production and Politics Affect Road Maintenance Efficiency: The Case of Uganda

Makerere University

Kampala, Uganda

Post Graduate Certificate: Resource Mobilization

Kampaia, Oganda

Makerere University 2012

**Post Graduate Certificate: Monitoring and Evaluation** 

Kampala

Makerere University 2012

Post Graduate Certificate: Logistics and Supply Management

Kampala

Kingston University 2010

#### M.A: International Economics

United Kingdom

Thesis title: Exchange rates and the trade balance in Uganda

Makerere University 2008

**B.A. Arts**: **Education**, with merit

Kampala, Uganda

### **Publications**

• KATUNZE, M. (2020, November). Contracting out and quality of road maintenance service in Uganda using panel data. In 2020 Annual Conference Evidence to enhance inclusive growth: Inclusive growth in Mozambique—scaling up research and capacity.

- Katunze, M; Kuteesa, A., Mijumbi, T., and Mahebe, D., (2017) Uganda warehouse receipt systems: Improving market performance and productivity. African Development Review, 29(S2), 135-146
- Katunze, M and Kuteesa, A. (2016) Uganda's revealed comparative advantage in COMESA. Journal of sustainable development, 9(3), 192-207.
- Guloba, M., Katunze, M., Ssewanyana, S., Ahikire, P., Musiimenta, D., Boonabaana, D., & Ssennono, V. (2018). Gender Roles and the Care Economy in Ugandan Households: The case of Kaabong, Kabale and Kampala districts.
- Munyambonera E., Katunze, M., Munu, M.L., and Sserunjongi, B., (2018) Expanding the pension sector in Uganda. Economic Policy Research Centre, Research Series 143.
- Katunze, M; Kuteesa, A., Mijumbi, T., and Mahebe, D., (2017) Uganda warehouse receipt systems: Improving market competitiveness and service delivery. Economic Policy Research Centre, Research series 137.
- Lakuma, P., Katunze M., Nagawa, M., Mawejje, J., Lwanga, M., Mbowa, S., and Shinyekwa, I. (March 2017) Country reviews of capacity development: the case of Uganda, Economic Policy Research Centre Occasional Paper No.41.
- Ahaibwe, G., Lakuma, P., Katunze, M. and Mawejje, J. (2016) Socio-Economic Effects of Gambling in Uganda, Economic Policy Research Centre research series No.126.
- Shinyekwa, I. and Katunze M. (2016) Assessment of the effect of the EAC common external tariff sensitive products list on the performance of domestic industries, welfare, trade and revenue, EPRC Research Series No. 129.
- FAO. 2014. Analysis of public expenditure in support of food and agriculture in Uganda, 2006/07-2012/13. Technical notes series, MAFAP, by Shinyekwa, I., Katunze, M. and Ahmed, M., Rome.
- Mwaura, F., Katunze, M., Muhumuza, T., & Shinyekwa, I. (2014) Budget Analysis and Assessment
  of Investments in Water Smart Agriculture for Smallholders in Uganda and East Africa, Occasional
  paper,36, Care International Uganda, EPRC & Global Water Initiative East Africa (GWI). Policy
  briefs and fact sheets
- Katunze, M. and Sserunjongi, B. (2018) Pension coverage: How inclusive is Uganda's social security system? Economic Policy Research Centre, Fact Sheet No.16. Katunze M. (2017) Improving the warehouse receipt system in Uganda. Economic Policy Research Centre, Policy Brief No. 90.
- Ahaibwe, G., Lakuma, P., Katunze, M. and Mawejje, J. (2016) Socio-Economic Effects of Gambling on welfare: Evidence from Kampala city, Economic Policy Research Centre Policy Brief No.61.
- Ahaibwe, G., Lakuma, P., Katunze, M. and Mawejje, J. (2016) the extent of gambling in Kampala city. Economic Policy Research Centre Policy Brief No.60.
- Kuteesa, A., and Katunze, M. (2016) Creating an enabling policy environment for agricultural finance to support climate risk management in Uganda. Economic Policy Research Centre policy brief No. 64.
- Kuteesa, A. and Katunze, M. (2016) the role of the private sector in incentivizing the uptake of climate-resilient seeds in Uganda. Economic Policy Research Centre Policy brief No. 65.

- Shinyekwa, I., Munu, M., and Katunze, M. (2016) has the common external tariff of sensitive list of products for the EAC generated intra-export trade? Economic Policy Research Centre policy brief No.73.
- Katunze M., and Mwaura, F. (2014) Water for Agricultural Production: Planning and Investment Dilemmas in Uganda, Fact Sheet 15, Care International Uganda, Economic Policy Research Centre & Global Water Initiative East Africa (GWI).
- Mwaura, F., & Katunze M. (2014) Enhancing agricultural production and productivity in Uganda through irrigation. Policy Brief No.49, Care International Uganda, Economic Policy Research Centre & Global Water Initiative East Africa (GWI).

## **Blogs**

- Efficient ways to extend hand washing to all Ugandans, 2020/05:22, The Economic misfit
- Unleashing women's leadership potential in Farmer Groups as a pathway to Agricultural transformation, 2017/07:07 (with Florence Nakazzi)
- What gaps exist in Uganda's warehouse receipt system? 2017/07:13.
- The need to focus on the growing number of underemployed persons in Uganda's labor force, 2017/04:17 (with Madina Guloba)

## Languages

English (Fluent) Luganda (Fluent), French (Good)

#### **Professional Affiliations**

 Member, Uganda Economics Association (UEA), African Growth and Development Policy Modelling Consortium (AGRODEP), African Economic Research Consortium (AERC), UNCTAD institute, Young African Researchers in Agriculture (YARA)

#### **Professional contributions**

• Reviewer: African Development Review, Gender in Management: an International Journal, British Journal of Economics, Management and Trade (BJEMT), Journal of Economics and Trade (JET),

#### **Additional Information**

### Media articles

- Pension liberalization bill unlikely to be passed in 2018, the Observer, 2018/01:29
- Why African Women should participate in private sector decision-making, News24African.com, 2016/04:03
- Here is how Uganda can benefit from AGOA and other trade opportunities, the Monitor, 2015/06:15 (with Alex T. Ijjo)
- Harmonize Investment of Water for Agriculture, the Observer, 2014/09:14
- Addressing challenges of the private sector in the EAC, the New vision, 2014/02:20

#### **Projects and Grants Handled**

2021: Lingnan University conference sponsorship (RCF-018/2021 HK\$ 791.50)

2020: Lingnan University conference sponsorship (RCF-016/1920 HK\$ 1189.44)

UNUWIDER conference sponsorship

2019: Lingnan University field trip sponsorship (RCF-053/1819 HK\$ 8,881)

2018: Lingnan University postgraduate studentship

Lingnan University School of graduate studies grant for project title: Social media tax and lifestyle patterns: an ex-ante analysis of Ugandan youth (Grant number: SLRP2018a 4 HK\$ 14,019)

UNDP project title: Understanding land dynamics and livelihoods in refugee-hosting districts of Northern Uganda

2017: OXFAM grant for project title: Women Economic Empowerment: Household Care Survey (Approximately, USD 50,000)

2016: African Economic Conference travel and accommodation grant (USD 1,772.67)

PEGNET conference travel and accommodation grant (USD 500)

2015: Global Development Conference travel and accommodation grant

International Institute of Sustainable Development (IISD) for project title: Private sector investment in changing climate: Resilient Rice value chain development in Uganda

DFID grant for project title: Implementing the capacity development component of the Development Research Uptake in Sub Saharan Africa (€92,000).

2014 Global Water Initiative and CARE Uganda grant for project title: Budget Analysis and Assessment of Investments in Water Smart Agriculture for Smallholders in Uganda and East Africa (USD 51,512).

FAO grant for project title: Monitoring African Food and Agricultural Policies, Analysis of Public

Expenditure towards Agricultural Sector of Uganda (Gates foundation grant number: OPP1164455).

2013: World Bank grant project: International Trade Statistics in Uganda (USD 7000)

2004: Government tertiary education scholarship,

## **Conferences and Seminars**

## As presenter

2021

EcoMod2021 International Conference on Modelling and Data Science; Postgraduate conference on interdisciplinary learning, Lingnan University Hong Kong; Research findings -Department of Economics Lingnan University 15<sup>th</sup> March.

2020

Evidence to enhance inclusive growth, UNUWIDER online conference 2-5 November 2020; Virtual global development finance conference, Africa growth institute SA 18-19th November; brown bag seminar-Department of Economics Lingnan University 5<sup>th</sup> November; Research findings seminar-Department of Economics Lingnan University 17<sup>th</sup> April 2019

Postgraduate Conference on Interdisciplinary learning, Lingman University Hong Kong29-30 March; Topic defence seminar- Department of Economics Lingman University 11<sup>th</sup> April

5-7 December 2017: 11th African Economic Conference, Abuja Nigeria

17-21 October 2016: 3rd National Women's week, Kampala Uganda

15-16 September 2016: PEGNET 2016 conference, Kigali Rwanda

11 13 June 2015: 16<sup>th</sup> Annual Global Development Conference, Casablanca Morocco

## As organizer

12 Sept 2013: Trade and regional integration Conference, Kampala Uganda

# **REFEREES**

- 1. Prof Voon Jan Piaw, Associate Professor- Department of Economics, Lingnan University, jvoon@ln.edu.hk
- **2.** Dr Isaac Shinyekwa, Senior Research Fellow-Trade and Integration Department, Economic Policy Research Centre Uganda, <a href="mailto:ishinyekwa@eprcug.org">ishinyekwa@eprcug.org</a>
- **3.** Dr Madina Guloba, Senior Research Fellow-Microeconomics Department, Economic Policy Research Centre, Uganda, mguloba@eprcug.org